Name: RISHANTH KUGATHAS

Location: Watford, Hertfordshire (Can Relocate UK Wide)

Mobile: 07387367106

Email: rishanth.kugathas@gmail.com

Availability: By Arrangement

Visa Status: 5 Year Limited Leave to Remain – EU Pre-settled status

PROFILE

An accomplished, adaptable, and enthusiastic IT Engineer, with extensive experience in technical support. Confident and versatile with far-reaching and varied knowledge across a broad range of clients and employers, both in the public and private sectors, and an in-depth understanding of a diversity of detailed business principles and practices. Achievement driven, motivated and versatile IT Professional with an analytical mind, certified skills and more than 10 years' experience supporting users, networks, technologies, platforms, and infrastructure. Extensive knowledge of windows desktop and server operating systems, Microsoft applications and advanced network abilities with cable management (patching). Proven track record of troubleshooting different types of IT issues underpinned by exceptional customer service and an aptitude for dealing with difficult customers/stressful situations. Demonstrates a winning mindset, a strong work ethic and a 'can do' attitude to support users and learn new skills to keep abreast of changing needs and tools to stay ahead of the curve. Excellent communication and interpersonal skills well suited to fast-paced, customer led and challenging environments. Ideally seeking an IT role in the Finance, Travel or Transport sectors, having successfully contracted as a limited company for global brands.

Rishanth is flexible on the location of future contracts.

ACHIEVEMENTS & HIGHLIGHTS

- A wealth of technical knowledge, skills and experience supported by passing globally recognised IT professional certifications
- Provided comprehensive technical support to 1000 users across various operating systems, applications, software and hardware
- Assisted with a network installation for 200 workstations, 12 servers, 8 multifunction printers, and 20 communication rooms
- Reduced workstation set up time by developing a disk cloning procedure to streamline operating system implementation and security properties configuration
- Good knowledge of Microsoft Applications, Dell PC & Server equipment, HP PC & Server equipment & Lenovo PC equipment
- Experienced with PC imaging software for OS deployment, Microsoft Office products and system security updates/patches
- Desktop experience includes Hardware/Software, Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7/8/8.1/10 and MS Office versions from 2011 - 2016
- At ease with setting up, configuration and overall management of the latest mobile devices such as IOS, Android & Blackberry
- ServiceNow proficient to manage tickets using remote desktop software such as Remote Desktop, VNC and Team Viewer
- Closing 35 45 tickets a day

KEY SKILLS SUMMARY

- DHCP, DNS, Ethernet, Wi-Fi
- Microsoft Office Applications
- Mac & Linux, Ubuntu & KDE
- IT Service Management
- Remedy & Cherwell Tools
- Registries/Permission/Drivers
- Cable Management
- Antivirus Programs

- Patching Issues
- ServiceNow Proficient
- End-User Training
- Scheduled Maintenance
- Shell Scripting
- Hardware/Software Support
- VNC/RDP Type Software
- Remote Desktop Support

Professional Experience

Omnicom / Unisys

Desktop Site Support

Aug 2018 - March 2019

- 1st Line / 2nd line Desktop Support
- Logging and closing over 120 tickets a week
- Working with both Windows (7/8/8.1/10) and Mac OSX (10.13)
- IOS and Android Mobile devices support
- Office 2016 MFA installation / configuration and setup
- Basic AD Support (Account Unlock, Password Resets)
- Supporting 42 + different agency
- Desktop and Laptop Installation & Configurations.
- Installation & Configuration of Printers
- Working in a Tech Bar type environment accepting walk-ins
- Installation of agency specific software's

Hemmersbach / WPP July 2017 – April 2018

Team Leader / Deployment Engineer / 2nd Line Desktop Support

- Deployment of Windows 10 image through PXE Service.
 - Migration of Users data via USMT.
 - Application Installs for users.
 - QC on deployed laptops to ensure that it meets the company's policy.
 - Configuration and setup of office 365.
 - 1st/2nd line Desktop support via Floor walk.
 - Managing a team of 5 Engineers
 - Providing up to date documentation and checklists for the engineer's onsite.
 - Provided training to all the engineers on site with the operational procedures as outlined in the documentation and checklist.
 - Familiarisation of Windows 10 for all the users for the office.
 - Floor walking support for hardware and software

Central Bedfordshire Council

April 2017 - July 2107

Deployment / Migration Engineer

- Deployment of Laptops and MacBook Air for Central Bedfordshire Council Employees.
- Floor walking support for Hardware and Software.
- Active Directory administration with MS Server 2012.

Robert Half Technology

May 2016 - Nov 2016

Desktop Support Engineer

- Support of Desktop, Laptop, Servers
- Windows 7 deployment. Building and imaging using SCCM, PXE boot.
- Active Directory and Exchange administration
- Hardware and software refresh.
- Diagnosed L1/L2 Network problems.
- Floor walking support for hardware and Software
- Incident management using ServiceNow, Closing 35 45 tickets a day.
- Being an effective interface between Customers, Internal Support Teams and 3rd Service Providers.

Expedia Oct 2015 - Mar 2016

L1/L2 Desktop Support Engineer

- Support of Laptop / Desktop / Servers / Switches.
- Arranged the repair and fixes of systems that were covered under outsourced maintenance agreements and warranties

- Delivered on-site support for Cisco products such as Video Teleconference systems, as well as Avaya VoIP solutions
- Worked as a team to support in-house Expedia applications and operating systems including MAC, Windows 7, 8, 8.1 & 10
- Configured software on end user systems and supported network related issues, including security and LAN connections
- Supported users by phone, email, in person and remotely throughout American cities in different states and locations
- Engaged with hardware and software vendors to ensure that new equipment was installed and ready to operate on schedule
- Incident management using ServiceNow, Closing 25 35 tickets a day

TEKsystems Sept 2015 – Oct 2015

Service Desk Engineer - Tier 2

- Supported company users on-site or via phone, email or remotely to address technical complications and downtime.
- Implemented an in-depth audit of existing IT company hardware and recommended changes to boost performance.
- Mentored and trained new company employees on system procedures, policies, functionality, and overall
 efficiency.
- Installed software and hardware on company machines and ensured maintenance levels were upheld for repairs.
- Increased efficiency by 25% by composing shell scripts to automate tasks during the deployment of desktop/laptops.
- Configured security measures for networks and performed comprehensive system imaging for 500+ laptops/ desktops.
- Floorwalking for hardware and software support

Coast Vancouver Airport Hotel

Nov 2014 - Sept 2015

Desktop Support Engineer

- Provided technical support on tickets that require more extensive troubleshooting and knowledge.
- Complete machine builds and verification
- Floor walking for hardware and software support
- User account setup and verification
- Advanced software installs
- Warranty and RMA support
- Provided after-hours on-call support
- Being an effective interface between Customers, Internal Support Teams and 3rd Service Providers.
- Ensure that all records and documents are completed in an accurate, concise, and articulate way including but not limited to Incident and Service Request tickets.
- Interpreted technical or procedure manuals on behalf of non-technical Customers and provides routine training in normal usage of services and systems

S & N Computer, Sydney, Australia

June 2014 – Nov 2014

Computer Network Engineer

- Designed and supported small computer networks, connections, and cabling based on customer bespoke needs
- Supported teams of end users on-site and remotely and created bespoke shell scripts to automate tasks and save time
- Resolved system failures to enhance the long-term efficiency of networks in terms of usability, speed, and adaptability
- Fixed minor or major problems/bugs, and reviewed network performance to speed up communication for the users
- Forward planned systems testing and scheduled upgrades for maintenance without impacting productivity and output
- Backed up data to protect the integrity of information and generated reports for senior staff on network connection issues
- Migrated all laptops from XP to Windows 7, Office 2010 and SCCM.

Transport for New South Wales, Sydney, Australia

Nov 2010 - June 2014

Intern/Graduate Program - Supervised Technicians and 4 Technical Staff

 Installed/configured computer hardware and performed scheduled maintenance upgrades to overcome technical issues

- Created and deleted accounts for staff and diagnosed faults with hardware, equipment, peripherals, and software
- Updated systems with records of software licenses and recorded stock inventory of equipment and other supplies
- Performed incident management for requests and assisted with the coordination for office moves, floor layouts and infrastructure

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS & EDUCATION

UNSW 2008 - 2012

Bachelors of Engineering Science (BEngSC) Telecommunications